Justin Miranda

https://www.justin-miranda.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-miranda

Orlando, FL • 850-902-6792 • justinmiranda@knights.ucf.edu

SUMMARY:

Computer Science Senior. Very strong background in object-oriented programming. Strong background in full stack development. Background in tutoring programming and math at the collegiate level. Talented in creating my own projects to gain industry experience. Highly skilled at communication and problem solving.

SKILLS:

Programming Languages: C, C++, C#, Java 8, Python 3, JavaScript, HTML 5, SCSS, CSS, Pug

Database: MongoDB, Heroku, Adminer, PostgreSQL, MySQL

IDEs: Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio Community, Eclipse, Android Studio **Frameworks:** Node JS, Express, Mongoose, Flask, SQL Alchemy ORM, Bootstrap

Webserver: Apache

Operating Systems: Windows, iOS, Ubuntu, CentOS, Android

Project Management Software: Github

EXPERIENCE:

C Tutor / Math Tutor

Feb 2017-Present

Valencia College

- Sole C programming tutor on Winter Park campus assisting students in best programming practices.
- Tutoring via Zoom which used to be face-to-face.
- Assist 1 to 7 students at a time understand arrays, basic algorithms and functions, memory, and pointers.
- Assist 1 to 10 students at a time in Developmental Math, Pre- Algebra, Intermediate Algebra, College Algebra, Calculus I, II, III, Differential Equations, Discrete Math, Statistics and College Math for Non-STEM Majors

Full Stack Developer

June 2020 to July 2020

BookR8r.herokuapp.com

- Environment: Python, Flask, BootStrap, PostgreSQL, Adminer, Heroku, HTML, and CSS.
- Created and designed a book rating platform that takes APIs from goodreads.com for the ratings and reviews values and presents them for users to view.
- Users can register, login, logout, search books within the database, review books, and rate books.
- Implemented a python program that uploaded 5000 comma-separated books to the Heroku database.

Game Developer

May 2020 to June 2020

Rocket Pilot

- Environment: Unity, VS Code, C#, Audacity
- Project involving a 2-D platformer rocket game that allows users to control its flight.
- Programmed the controls and level success/failure events.
- Created prefab objects for faster level creation.
- Wrote and recorded the music.

JavaScript Back End Development

January 2020 to April 2020

Mango Greenhouse

Environment: Node.js, JavaScript, VS Code, React, MongoDB, Express.js

- Involved in a group project developing a web and mobile application that would give users the temperature, humidity, and UV light indices for their personal greenhouse.
- Created the backend APIs in JavaScript for the web application that synched with a Particle iO board which posted information on current conditions to act as a greenhouse application.
- API development with async functions utilizing Express and MongoDB Management with Mongoose.

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida – Orlando, FL GPA: 2.93 January 2018 to May 2021 Bachelor of science Degree in Computer Science, Minor in Secure Computing And Networks (SCAN)

Relevant Courses

• Processes of Object-Oriented Software, Cyber Security, Cryptography, Comp Sci I & II, System Software, Discrete I & II, Java & C Programming and many more.

REFERENCES

Pasha Utt

VP Java Developer Team Lead at Citi

uttpasha@gmail.com

Lisa Keeton

Valencia College Tutor Manager

<u>Ikeeton@valenciacollege.edu</u>